on line six of this code
we invoke the meal method and
output the return value of that method
invocation
with the method p
this time we use p instead of put s to
output the return
value of the method and we'll talk about
why we do that in just a moment
now let's look at the method definition
of meal
on line two we see the string dinner
but we don't do anything with it we
don't output the string dinner on line
two
and that's not the return value of the
meal method
moving on to line three we call put s
to output the string dinner
so we can expect that when line three of
the meal method
is executed the string dinner will be
printed
this is the last line executed in the
meal method
so what will the return value of the
mill method be
on this last line line three we have a
method invocation
we call the put s method and the return
value of calling put s
is always nil when we call put s
on line three of this method we output
the string dinner
and return nil because this method call
to put s
is also the last line executed in the
meal method
the return value of meal will also be
nil
so we expect that our call to put us on
line three will output the string dinner
and the call to p on line six outputting
the return value of the meal method
will output nil
let's run our code
and we see the expected results here
now the reason that we used p
to output the return value of invoking
the meal method
on line six is so the return value
nil would be visible in our output
when you call put s to output a return
value of nil
you see a blank line
so to see more clearly that the return
value
of invoking meal is nil we can call p
and see that nil printed to the screen
you